DANIEL MCINTYRE

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer familiar with wide range of programming utilities and languages. Knowledgeable of backend and frontend development requirements.

My passion for finding solutions to problems in addition to working with and managing teams is highlighted through over a decade of experience in pervious strategic communications-based roles.

EDUCATION

Certificate of Technical Studies, Web Development, 04/2022

Juno College of Technology - Toronto, ON

Bachelor of Arts, Media Studies, 2013

University of Guelph - Toronto, ON

Diploma, Public Relations, 2013

Humber College - Toronto, ON

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Full Stack Web Developer, 11/2022 - Current

Freelance, Toronto, ON

• Full Stack Web Developer specializing in building responsive and accessible web applications.

Web Development Student Mentor, 11/2022 - Current

Juno College of Technology, Toronto, ON

 Web Development mentor for students, assisting them with learning web development technologies as well as de-bugging code and towards a solution.

Lead Software Developer, 05/2022 - 08/2022

Co. Lab, Toronto, ON

• Lead Application Developer in shipping a product in collaboration with a cross-functional team.

Manager of Communications, 05/2021 - 10/2021

College of Kinesiologists of Ontario, Toronto, ON

 Managed all internal and external communications material and media, including website operated through WordPress.

Manager of Communications, 03/2016 - 12/2020

Patients Canada, Toronto, ON

 Responsible for all Communications and overseeing the re-development of Patient's Canada's website, including implementing front and back-end features. Also managed the CiviCRM database system.

Manager of Client Services, 03/2016 - 12/2020

Grosso McCarthy Inc., Toronto., ON

 Trained and directed the Communications team and developed client proposals leading to acquisition of new clients for the firm.



Toronto, ON M5T2W9



905-965-1234



daniel-mcintyre@hotmail.com

WEBSITE, PORTFOLIO, PROFILES

- danielcodes.ca
- github.com/DanielMcIntyre2022
- linkedin.com/in/daniel-mcintyre2022

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Fundamentals

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- Responsive Design

JavaScript Libraries & Frameworks

- React JS
- Vue JS
- Angular JS
- Next JS
- Meteor JS
- Redux / Redux Toolkit

Backend

- REST APIs
- Node JS
- Express
- Mongo DB
- Firebase

CSS Libraries & Frameworks

- SASS
- Bootstrap
- Tailwind CSS

Third-Party APIs

- SendGrid
- Stripe

Development & Deployment

- Git / GitHub
- Netlify
- Heroku
- Railway

PROFESSIONAL PROJECTS

Dan's E-Commerce

LIVE SITE: https://dans-e-commerce.up.railway.app/

REPO: https://github.com/DanielMcIntyre2022/FINAL-E-Comm-Portfolio-Web-App

A full-stack MongoDB, Express, React, Node (MERN) E-Commerce Web Application.

Made with Tailwind CSS and Material UI CSS frontend libraries and utilizes Redux toolkit for state management.

Created backend JSON REST API to fetch and create user/product data and JSON web tokens (JWT) to handle user authentication and authorization.

Includes integration of Firebase database storage for product images and includes Stripe API to handle user payments.

Socialite

LIVE SITE: https://soicalite.netlify.app/

REPO: https://github.com/DanielMcIntyre2022/Social-Lite-Application

A full-stack event planning application built with React in the front-end and Node JS/firebase in the back end.

Video Diary

LIVE SITE: https://video-diary.netlify.app/

REPO: https://github.com/DanielMcIntyre2022/Video-Diary-App

An application built in React, Video Diary uses Google's YouTube API and firebase. Fetches and displays the current global trending videos on YouTube. Users can also search for their desired video and save them to view later or delete from the page.

Giphy Sentiment

LIVE SITE: https://giphy-sentiment-39.netlify.app/

REPO: https://github.com/DanielMcIntyre2022/project-4-giphy-sentiment

An application built in React, Giphy Sentiment utilizes the Giphy API and Firebase. Users can search for Giphy's that matches their mood and save their desired gifs to view later.

Movie Mood

LIVE: https://eager-curran-c5f5e6.netlify.app/

REPO: https://github.com/DanielMcIntyre2022/MovieMood

An application built using HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript and the MovieDB REST API, MovieMood fetches movies the user can watch based on their input of genre and time period for the last 100 years.